（忆往昔）
你应该不熟悉奥莉薇特
The name Olivette means little to you.
她是大巫师团的高层人物
A high-ranking member of the grand coven,
指控我的那个人
the one who led the charge against me.
她刚刚来到了美国
She's just come back to the states.
现在出击正合适
Now would be an excellent time to strike.
干掉一个讨厌的老巫婆
and take out a miserable, old witch.
她已经跟我作对几个世纪了
who's been standing in my way for centuries.
- 母亲 没戏了 - 什么
- Mother, it's not happening. - What?
临时有事 奥莉薇特不急
Something's come up. Olivette can wait.
我的安宁就是帮助他人 查案子
My peace is helping people. Working cases.
我就想干这个
That's all I want to do.
这跟血印有关吗
Is this about the mark?
我不想再纠结于治愈方法了 萨姆
I'm done trying to find a cure, Sammy.
但答案不在外面 答案就是我
The answer is not out there. It's with me.
所以在力竭之前 我会继续抗争
So, I'm gonna fight it till I can't fight it anymore.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
你以为呢 我要离开
What's it look like? I'm leaving.
又想摆布我
Another petty manipulation.
你想从我这里得到什么
What do you want from me?!
看到你变成
Why it breaks my heart.
这样的笨蛋让我多么伤心
to see what a colossal numb nut you've become?!
坐在王座上 可悲 无聊的小孩子
Sad, bored, wee boy on the throne.
那对巴不得你死掉的猎人
who'll flop ass-up the second those Winchesters.
温家兄弟 一开口找你 你就会立刻
hunters who'd as soon see you dead as have you to tea …
招之即来
ask you to.
你是他们的走狗
You're their bitch.
（如今）
（马萨诸塞州 伍斯特）
我憎恶自己的罪孽 因您的惩罚是公正的
I detest all my sins because of thy just punishment.
但更重要的是 这些罪孽触犯了您 上帝
but most of all because they offend thee, my god,
您是至善的 我应全心爱您
who art all good and deserving of all my love.
我确信 有您的恩助
I firmly resolve, with the help of thy grace,
我将不再犯下罪孽 远离罪孽
to sin no more and to avoid the near occasion of sin.
阿门
Amen.
我宽恕你的罪孽
I absolve you of your sins.
以圣父圣子圣灵之名
In the name of the father and of the son and of the holy spirit.
阿门
Amen.
安心走吧 泰瑞
Go in peace, Terry.
周日见
See you Sunday.
好的 神父
That you will, father.
[邪恶力量 第10季第16集]
陛下
Majesty.
求您跟她说说吧
I beg you to speak with her.
又怎么了
What now?
您母亲依然在
Your mother remains…
生您的气
vexed with your highness.
而她把气都撒在了朝臣上
and vents her frustration by abusing the court.
当然没人敢还击
No one dares retaliate, of course,
当然 在地狱必然是要受折磨的
and, yes, one expects to suffer in hell,
但我恐怕已经受够了
but I fear I've reached my limit.
就是说
To wit…
真受不了了
I mean, seriously.
母亲
Mother!
陛下什么事
Yes, your royal highness?
要说两句吗
You care to comment?
令人惊叹 施法者法术高超
Magnificent work by an astonishing talent.
厉害
Mm, brava!
我一直就说你是个两面派
I always said you were two-faced.
听着 妈妈 够了
Look, mommy, enough.
我知道你生我气
I know you're annoyed with me.
生你气 不 费格斯
Annoyed? No, Fergus.
我是伤心欲绝 遭到背叛
I'm devastated, betrayed.
心碎成渣
and brokenhearted.
就因为我不肯替你去
Because I wouldn't go begging to a bunch of witches.
求一群女巫
on your behalf?
大巫师团是巫师界的至高领袖
The grand coven is the supreme command of all witchcraft.
没有他们的允许 我是不能施法的
Without their sanction, I'm forbidden to practice!
抱歉 我没发现你停手了啊
Forgive me. I hadn't noticed you'd stopped.
那个吗 小法术而已
That? Parlor trick.
我是能做大事的人
I'm capable of greatness.
如果不受束缚 我的能力不可估量
Given free reign, I'd be unstoppable.
我真是很想
I am this close.
把你丢回地牢去
to throwing you back into that dungeon.
当然 为什么不呢
Of course. Why not?
你除了让我难过 为什么还要做别的呢
Why do anything but cause me more pain?
你不肯在奥莉薇特和巫师团的事上
Bad enough that you wouldn't intervene.
插手帮我就够糟糕了
with Olivette and the coven,
你还违抗我的意愿
but you went directly against my wishes,
站在温家兄弟那边
siding with those Winchesters,
不肯杀他们
refusing to kill them,
又把第一刃拱手交给他们
then delivering the first blade into their hands,
你明知道那武器能杀掉我们所有人
which you know could slaughter us all.
比起你亲娘 你更亲他们
You prefer them to your own flesh and blood.
真让人委屈啊 费格斯
It's a bitter pill, Fergus,
我为你做了那么多
after all I've done for you.
具体做了什么呢
And what exactly would that be?
我给了你生命 费格斯
I gave you life, Fergus.
没有我 小帅哥
Without me, sunshine,
你都不会存在
you wouldn't exist.
[咒语]
好吧 我觉得可能是诅咒
All right, so, I'm thinking, uh, curse, maybe.
萨姆 帮帮忙啊
Sam, a little help here, okay?
我想找事做呢
I'm trying to stay busy here.
专注于案子 不是血印
You know, eye on the ball, not on the mark.
除非能确定不是 这就是我们的案子
And this a case until we know it's not.
当然 你说得对
Sure. No, yeah, you're right.
两周三起自杀
Three suicides, two weeks.
不仅仅是自杀
They're not just suicides.
自己切腹
They gutted themselves.
而且还是慢慢来的
And they took their sweet time doing it.
肯定疼死了
I mean, that had to be incredibly painful.
而且被害人之间似乎并无联系
I can't seem to find any link between the vics, either.
是啊 很可能是诅咒
Yeah, probably a curse, I bet.
这个男子 他很帅吗
And this man, he was handsome?
特别帅
Exquisite.
让我无法呼吸
He took my breath away.
但我们被教导不要说太多
But we are told not to speak so much.
我们加入修道会前的事
of the time before we joined the order.
我们选择这种生活都是有原因的
We all found our way to this life for a reason.
他是你的原因吗
Was he yours?
他名叫皮耶罗 是个了不起的艺术家
His name was Piero, an incredible artist.
有时候 我会为他做模特
Sometimes, I would pose for him.
他说我是他的缪斯
And he called me his muse.
你可以想象
As you can imagine,
我们整日待在一起
we spent hours, days with each other.
跟他在一起 我觉得好自由
I felt so free with him.
我
I…
此前从未像那样亲近过一个男人
had never been close with a man before that.
后来呢
So…what happened?
我
I…
我现在不能说
I can't right now.
没事的
It's okay.
真的
Really.
我们很像 知道吗
We're a lot alike, you know?
我觉得我们进入修道院
I think we're supposed to enter the convent.
本该是有更崇高的目的
for some…higher purpose,
但我们很多人选择这条路
but many of us chose this.
却是因为那些
because of the things that…
让我们无力招架的事
overwhelmed us.
什么情况
All right, so, what do we got?
泰瑞·斯隆 普通人 朋友不多
Terry Sloane, ordinary guy, not a lot of friends,
但也没有敌人 与其他被害人无联系
but no known enemies, no relation to the other vics.
未必啊
Well, not necessarily.
他是天主教徒 另两个也是
He's Catholic, and so are the other two.
迪恩 这是马萨诸塞州
Dean, this is Massachusetts.
马萨诸塞州的天主教徒是很多的
There are a lot of Catholics in Massachusetts.
你觉得这是案子吗
You think this is a case?
谁会用烛台自杀啊
Who kills himself with a candlestick, all right?
有数十亿种更好的办法好吗
There's about a billion better ways.
是啊 但他确实是自杀
Yeah, but he did kill himself.
那么就不是女巫
All right, so, it was not a witch.
他身上没什么巫术的东西
There was nothing hexy found on him.
附身 或许是恶魔
Uh, possession? Could have been a demon?
但恶魔附身活人的目的
Yeah, but the point of a demon possessing a living thing is to,
就是看重他是活的啊
you know, possess a living thing.
好吧 探员 你把手机拿回
Okay, agent, why don't you get that cellphone.
局里的犯罪实验室
back to the bureau's crime lab,
像你对那些人说的那样黑进去
get it hacked like you told those guys,
我们好查查泰瑞·斯隆在搞些什么
and, uh, we'll figure out what's going on with Terry Sloane.
大概只有裸体自拍
Probably nude selfies.
我觉得这案子有门
I'm feeling good about this.
阿门
Amen.
亲爱的
Hi, sweetie.
去睡吧 弗兰克
You need to come to bed, Frank.
你晚上干那么久
You got to be exhausted.
肯定累坏了
from all those night hours you've been putting in.
是啊
Yep, yep.
这工作越来越不好干了
The old job's gotten pretty demanding, all right.
撒谎
Liar.
天呐 不 不
Oh, my god. No! No!
弗兰克
Frank!
我无法相信
I just can't believe.
莉莎·麦卡锡会杀了她丈夫
Lisa McCarthy would murder her husband.
她身上沾满了他的血
Right, well, his blood was all over her body.
捅死她丈夫的剪刀上
And her prints were all over.
也都是她的指纹
the pair of scissors that butchered him.
- 太可怕了 - 是啊
- That's terrible. - Yeah.
但我们还是有些问题
Now, we also have some questions.
首先 她完全不记得这事
Um, for starters, she has no memory of it.
她最后记得的事就是在这里
The last thing she remembers is being here.
弗兰克去忏悔了
Frank had gone to confession.
所以 如果他在忏悔时说了什么
So, if he happened to say anything in the confession.
关于跟妻子有矛盾的话
about, you know, maybe problems with the wife…
抱歉 但忏悔是理应保密的
I'm sorry. The nature of confession is confidential.
神父 所有被害人都来你的教堂
Father, all of the victims attended your church.
你能至少告诉我们
Um, could you at least tell us.
这些人是否最近做过忏悔吗
if they had recently been to confession?
是的
Yes.
他们几个都定期来
These men were fairly regular,
但是这里大多数人都是如此
but then, so are the majority of the folks here.
神父
Father?
二位探员 马赛厄斯修女是社会服务主任
Agents, Sister Mathias is our director of social services.
我已经安排她带你们参观 解答你们的问题
I've asked her to show you around and answer any questions.
好的
Sure.
修女
Sister.
您叫
Agent…?
奥曼
Allman.
这位是贝茨探员
And this is Agent Betts.
修女 你知道最近接连发生的命案吧
Sister, you're aware of the recent string of deaths, right?
是的 真是可怕的惨剧
Yes, a terrible tragedy.
但我不太明白你们为什么来这儿
But I'm confused as to why you're here.
几起都是自杀 对吧
These were all suicides, weren't they?
可能不是
Well, possibly not.
是谋杀吗
Murders?
杀人的方式都是一样的
Well, the actual method of killing was all identical.
犯罪手法吗
Ah, the M.O.
是的 犯罪手法
Yes, indeed. The M.O.
我去到处看看
I'm gonna go, uh have a look around.
失陪 修女
Uh, excuse me, sister.
贝茨探员…是奥曼探员
Agent Betts, uh, Allman.
好的
Okay.
修女 你注意到麦卡锡夫妇的生活
Uh, sister, d-did you notice, um, any change in the…
有什么变化吗
in the McCarthy's lives?
吵架 酗酒 出轨之类的
You know, fighting, drinking, cheating?
就一般那些问题
You know, the usual.
一般那些问题 有点愤世嫉俗啊
The usual. A bit cynical, agent?
剪刀捅肚子
Well, you know, scissors to the gut.
让人没法不悲观啊
really, uh, bring out the grinch in me.
那么
So…
莉莎·麦卡锡说
Now, Lisa McCarthy said that.
他们对彼此很忠诚
they were very devoted to each other.
是这样吗
Was that true?
似乎一直是如此
That always appeared to be the case.
但是
But…?
我们是在考虑动机 是吗
We're looking for a motive, aren't we?
是的
We are.
之前一名被害人的手机上有跟女友
An earlier victim's cellphone showed some angry texts.
争吵的短信
between he and his girlfriend.
因为他在乱搞
'cause he had been fooling around.
的确有传言
There were rumors.
弗兰克劈腿了吗 莉莎骗了我
So, Frank cheated on Lisa. So, she lied to me.
她不知道啊
Oh, she didn't know.
我的消息来源没问题
My sources are excellent.
但你不是听我说的
And you didn't hear it from me.
我有个问题
I got a question.
你这样的人
How does someone, uh, like you.
怎么会
end up, you know…?
避世隐居吗
Cloistered away from the world?
你是在取笑我吗 奥曼探员
Are you making fun of me, Agent Allman?
没有
No. No, no. I, uh…
我只是想不通一个人怎么能
I guess I'm just wondering how somebody quits.
退出一种生活 选择另一种完全不同的生活
one life for something completely different.
还能有如此坚定的信念
and… and then believe in it so much.
这个嘛
Well…
就我而言 我当时觉得别无选择
In my case, I felt I had no choice.
我的生活变得很痛苦
My life had become painful.
我感到绝望
There was hopelessness.
我觉得我必须找到
I felt I had to find.
比自己更重要的事去做
something larger than myself to focus on.
算是使命吧
A kind of mission, I guess.
你一定完全不能理解我的话吧
You have no idea what I'm talking about, I'm sure.
未必
Mm, don't be.
修女 我有个问题
Sister. I got a question.
肯定跟我的问题不一样
I'm sure it's a different question.
这附近有公墓吗
Is there a cemetery nearby?
算是吧
You could say that.
整个教堂就是建在墓室上的
The entire church is built over burial crypts.
那你有没有听到 或感到
Have you ever, uh, heard or… or felt.
什么奇怪 不寻常的事
anything strange or unusual?
怎么个不寻常法
Unusual how?
比如教堂内有没有冷点
Like, uh, spots in the building that suddenly get cold.
或者让你觉得自己…
or, uh… or maybe you feel like you're not…
不是一个人的地方
not quite alone?
链条作响 茶杯飞过房间吗
Rattling chains and teacups that fly across the room?
修女 你是在取笑我吗
Sister, are you making fun of me?
不是吧
Really?
联调局相信鬼魂
The FBI believes in ghosts?
恐怕我并不信
I'm afraid I don't.
失陪了 二位探员 我还有工作
If you'll excuse me, agents, I have to get back to work.
你敢说你不觉得那个修女很性感吗
Tell me you didn't think that nun was hot.
而且我觉得她看上我了
I think she had a little thing for me, too.
迪恩 她已经许给耶稣了
Dean, she was married to jesus.
好吧
All right, so,
弗兰克劈腿他老婆莉莎了
Frank cheated on his wife, Lisa, all right?
整件案子
You know, the whole theme of this case.
似乎都是亏待了自己女人的男人
seems to be about guys doing their women wrong.
发现了吗
Notice that?
是啊 但莉莎·麦卡锡似乎的确
Yeah, but Lisa MacCarthy was pretty convincing.
不知道她杀了自己的丈夫
that she had no idea whatsoever she had killed her husband.
性感修女说莉莎也不知道他在劈腿
Oh, hot nun said that Lisa had no idea he was cheating on her.
或许她是被知道他劈腿的人控制了
So, maybe she was controlled by someone who did.
再说一遍 没发现巫术痕迹
Again, nothing witchy.
鬼呢
Ghost?
不好说 教堂的确有电磁干扰
Hard to say. I mean, there's EMF in the church,
但毕竟下面就是坟地
but it's built on a burial ground.
你知道所有被害人最近都进行过忏悔吗
You know that all the victims recently went to confession?
那你觉得德兰尼神父跟这事有关
So you think Father Delaney's involved?
也或许是告解室附近有什么东西
Or maybe something surrounding the confessional.
萨姆 我多久没去忏悔了
Sammy, how long has it been since my last confession?
你从来做过忏悔
You've never been to confession.
那真是太久了
Well, that's too long.
你召唤我吗
You summoned…
陛下
Your royal highness?
母亲
Mother.
他还记得呢
Oh, he remembers!
我能为你做什么吗
What can I do for you?
我能为你做点什么
It's what I can do for you.
我一直在思考 如果我存在的目的
I've been thinking just how wretched it would be.
也就是在世间造孽
if my own raison d'etre…
被人剥夺
wreaking havoc and pain on earth…
那我会多么痛苦
were taken from me.
我能体会你心里有多堵 我同情你
I see how stifled you must feel, and I sympathize.
那么你会为我去找大巫师团吗
Does this mean that you'll go to the grand coven on my behalf?
比那还好
Even better.
我把大巫师团找来给你了
I've brought the coven to you.
你认识奥莉薇特吧
I believe you know Olivette,
大巫师团的女祭司
High Priestess of the grand coven.
是开心得说不出话了吗
Speechless with joy?
你个死贱人
You utter bitch!
渣滓
Bottom-feeder!
暴风雨前的暴风雨啊
Ah, the storm before the storm.
你看到了 铁镣铐遏制了她的法力
As you can see, the iron chains render her powerless,
你可以向她陈情 或者实施报复
so you can plead your case, exact your revenge,
只要能让你开心就好
whatever it is that puts a spring back in your step.
你们好好玩吧
You kids have fun now.
看来你被流放期间
I see your time as outcast.
从卑鄙变成了可憎
has led you from vile to loathsome.
我看你羞辱我
I doubt this strategy of insults.
也无法摆脱困境吧
will get you out of this pickle.
是啊
Mm, no.
我才不会在与普通人生子的女人面前
I do not grovel before she who lay with a non-magic.
卑躬屈膝呢
and hatched his spawn.
我的私生活与你无关
My personal life was none of your business.
我本可成为你的明星
I could have been your superstar.
得了吧
Oh, please!
我们最初接纳你个忘恩负义的女人进入巫师团
When we initiated your thankless ass into the coven,
就是因为你法术高强才没介意你的不检点
we did overlook your private lapses because of your talent.
我们以为你慢慢就不会再那么鲁莽 自私
We thought you'd outgrow your reckless, selfish ways,
但没有 你反而越来越失控
but, oh, no, they just grew out of control.
看看你现在 跟恶魔勾结
And now look at you, consorting with demons.
好一番豪言
Quite the speech.
你可是站在我儿子的宫殿里
considering you're in my son's palace.
什么
What?
我儿子 你之前提到的那个
You see, my son, the spawn you speak of,
如今是地狱之王了
is now the king of hell.
完全是个灰姑娘的故事啊
Tall Cinderella story, I'd say.
没错
Oh, aye.
而你呢 亲爱的奥莉薇特
And now you, dearest Olivette,
是至恶之人和他尽心的母亲的
are prisoner of the baddest of the bad.
阶下囚了
and his devoted mummy.
你眼中带着忧伤
It was the sadness in your eyes.
我看到了自己的倒影
I saw myself there.
是因为皮耶罗吗
Was it Piero?
他是你来这里的原因吗
Is he the reason you're here?
疯狂和忠诚没多大区别
There is not much difference between madness and devotion.
我痴迷于他
I was obsessed with him.
我们分享彼此的秘密
We shared each other's secrets.
走在同一条路上
We were on the same road.
我突然意识到
I suddenly realized.
我是多么深地爱上了皮耶罗
how deeply in love with Piero I had fallen.
他说我开始为他做模特之后
He said it was only after I posed for him.
他的作品才拥有了真正的力量 和表现力
that his work took on real power, real expression.
我为他做模特的那幅画 开启了他的事业
The painting I had posed for was the beginning of his career.
最后 那幅画成了他的杰作
In the end, it was his masterpiece.
（意大利 佛罗伦萨）
我的感情生活中可没遇见过这么奇妙的事
Sweet jesus, nothing in my love life was ever so magical.
奇妙可能带来毁灭
Magic can be ruinous,
尤其如果你被耍弄
especially if the trick is on you.
我终于向皮耶罗倾吐了真心
I finally confessed my heart to Piero.
我觉得我们可以看透彼此的想法
I felt we could read each other's thoughts,
但我把内心的想法说了出来
but I said the words inside out loud…
「我爱你」
"I love you."
我等着 内心慢慢枯萎
I waited, dying inside.
然后
And then…
他说他对我的确有感情
He explained he had feelings for me…
但却不与我的感觉相同
…but not of the same sort.
他另有所爱吗
He loved another?
是啊
Indeed.
他的艺术
His art.
那对他来说就是一切
It was everything to him.
由于我影响了他的艺术 他在乎我
Insomuch that I affected it, he cared for me,
但除此之外 他对我也就只有友情
but beyond that, he could offer me nothing but friendship.
我是如此绝望
I fell into such despair.
我吃不下 睡不着
I could not eat nor sleep.
直到我的家人不能再忍受了
Until my family could stand no more.
所以你才加入了修道院吗
And that's when you entered the convent.
简直像我死了一样
It's as if I'd died.
我父亲送我去
My father sent me there.
好放下悲伤 忘记皮耶罗
to escape my sorrow and forget Piero.
他的仆人一天晚上把我从家中拽了出去
His servants dragged me from home one night.
这些我父亲的财产
All these things from my father's estate…
我那晚之后就再没见过了
I never saw them again after that night.
我曾经的一切都丢失了
Everything that was mine was lost to me…
除了我的日记
except my journal.
那些我无法对他人倾吐的话
Things I could say to no one,
也没有人想听的话
Things no one wanted to hear.
你是因为孤单…
Loneliness is…
是啊
Yes.
是的
It is.
也算意料之中
Well, I can't say I'm surprised.
你向来这么暴躁
You always were petulant.
鲁莽 自视甚高
and reckless and overrated.
放逐对你来说都是轻的了
Banishment was too good for you.
你一直嫉妒我的才华
You were always so envious of my skills,
你个蠢货
you fool.
我对巫师团唯一的威胁
The only threat I ever posed to the coven.
就是我比你更聪明 更有天赋
was that I was smarter, more gifted than you!
不知天高地厚
More blindly ambitious!
有何不可呢
Why not?
你们这些废物只会安于现状 躲躲藏藏
You nits were content to live in the shadows,
与黑猫厮混 玩玩扫帚
dicking around with black cats and broomsticks.
不求上进
instead of greatness.
这拳是干什么
What was that one for?
强调
Emphasis.
我会从你这儿得到我想要的
I will get what I want from you.
你休想
No, you won't.
因为你想要的已经不存在了
Because what you are looking for no longer exists.
巫师团不过是曾经强盛的破败遗迹
The coven is a pale relic of its past power,
被猎巫削弱 绑在木桩上烧死
weakened by witch hunts, burning at the stake,
无止尽的审判 都是他们操纵的
endless persecution, and all of it was engineered by them.
他们
Them?
你脑子没我想的那么好使嘛
Not as quick as I'd have thought.
好吧
All right!
一个道貌岸然的激进行善组织
It's a rabid group of sanctimonious do-gooders.
一心要致我们于死地
dedicated to our downfall.
他们和我们法力一样强大吗
They had equal magic?
更糟
Worse …
他们会公关
Public relations.
他们让教会和民众陷入恐慌
They whipped the church and public into a panic.
我们中最拔尖的都被杀了 或是隐姓埋名
Our best were killed or driven underground.
他们还掠夺了我们的咒语和秘密
They then plundered our spells and secrets.
都运走 藏在全世界各地的秘密地堡里
and shipped them to hidden bunkers all around the world.
看起来你恨他们比恨我更甚
It appears you hate them more than you do me.
他们想要摧毁我们的世界
They tried to destroy our world!
为了一己私欲 囤积不可估量的力量
Hoarding unbelievable power for their own amusement.
一群自命不凡 自以为是的混蛋
Smug, self-righteous bastards.
记录者
The men of letters.
在
Yes?
你好 神父
Hiya, father.
怎么是你
Pardon me?
宽恕你 难道不应该是你宽恕我吗
Pardon you? I thought it was the other way around.
我就是…
Just… It's…
我来是为了忏悔
So, uh, I'm here to … here to clean house.
我有事不吐不快
I need to get some things off my chest.
好的
All right.
请说
Continue.
是女人的事 神父
It's the women, father.
从何说起呢
Where do I begin?
大家一般会说 「保佑我 神父 我有罪」
"Bless me, father, for I have sinned, " is usual.
对 太好了
Right. Good. Yeah.
那句 还有…
So, that, and, um…
关于女人
So, the women.
这事我做的很不地道
Uh, and this is not something that I'm proud of,
我让那些姑娘以为和我在一起会有未来
but I let them think that we have more of a future than we do,
懂吗
you know?
吉娜
Ah, Gina.
Gina?
别误会
Well, now, don't get me wrong.
和她共度的时光 很美好
I mean, she was … it was good times.
你懂的 滚床单 她做的意面
I mean, you know how it is … the sex, the lasagna …
但我对她不忠
but I was not honest with her.
有时我还会找
And sometimes, I was seeing two,
别的小妞
maybe three girls at the same time,
有时候一天还见好几个
sometimes in the same day.
你能想象
You get the picture.
还不止是吉娜 我伤的妹子太多了
And it wasn't just Gina. It was endless.
这让我厌恶自己
It's making me sick.
你希望得到宽恕吗 孩子
And you wish to be forgiven, my son?
是的 我得端正自己的行为
I do. I need to clean up my act.
作为忏悔 你要说五遍「万福玛利亚」
As penance, you shall say five "Hail Mary"s,
和两遍「吾父」
two "Our Father"s,
并反思自己的罪过
and reflect on your transgression.
这就行了 然后我就没事了吗
And then, that's it? Then I'm good to go?
希望这能启发你自我反省
One would hope some… inner exploration might occur.
祷告只是为了引导你
The prayers are just the beginning.
进行深刻的灵魂反思
to some serious soul-searching.
还有别的想说的吗 奥曼探员
Is there anything else on your mind, Agent Allman?
我想说
What if I said I…
我还不想死
I didn't want to die…yet,
我还没准备好
you know, that I wasn't ready?
你觉得自己会死吗
Are you expecting to?
一直如此
Always.
我的生活 我的工作
You know, the life I live, the work I do…
我觉得
I pretty much just figured.
工作就是我的一切
that that was all there was to me, you know?
开着车四处奔走
Tear around and jam the key in the ignition.
一路奔到底 直到耗尽燃油
and haul ass until I ran out of gas.
我一直以为 有一天
I guess I just thought sooner or later,
我也会这样死去
I'd go out the same way that I live …
一脚油门踩到底 就这样
pedal to the metal, and that would be it.
那现在呢
But now?
现在
Now, um…
最近发生的事
Recent…events, uh…
让我意识到 也许我离死亡已经很近了
make me think I might be closer to that than I really thought.
我也说不好
And… I don't know.
有些事
I mean, you know, there's … there's things,
有些人 有些感觉 我…
there's…people, feelings that I-I-
我希望以一种与以往不同的方式去体验
I want to experience differently than I have before,
还有些是我想去体验
or maybe even for the first time.
再仔细说说 比吉娜那事儿深入点
Go a little deeper, perhaps, than with Gina.
好
Yeah.
我开始觉得
Yeah, I'm just starting to think that…
人生也许比我想得要丰富
maybe there's more to it all than I thought.
意识到宇宙之大
Learning there's more to the universe.
大过自我的小小世界 会令人惊恐
than your tiny world can be a frightening discovery.
你真的相信上帝吗 探员
Do you truly believe in god, agent?
那对你来说会是一种安慰
Because that can be a comfort.
我相信上帝的存在
I believe there is a god.
但我不知道 他是否还相信我们
But I am not sure he still believes in us.
那里有人偷听吗
So, you think you had an eavesdropper in there?
但愿吧
Hope so.
那你得小心了哦
You better watch your back.
如果我们是对的 像你这样的混蛋
If we're right, jerks like you.
正是那只鬼想要找的
are just what our ghost is looking for.
伊莎贝拉
Isabella?
伊莎贝拉 你在吗
Isabella? Are you here?
[拉丁文]
我在修道院也不得安宁
I found no peace in the convent,
我的悲伤变成了愤怒
and my sorrow turned to rage.
对皮耶罗的爱已经化为了仇恨
What was once love for Piero had become hatred.
一天夜里 我从窗户翻出 来到了他的画室
One night, I snuck out a window and made my way to his studio.
我不知道我为什么要去
I'm not sure why I went.
与他对峙
To confront him?
还是毁掉那幅画
To ruin the painting.
像他毁掉我的爱那样毁掉他的爱
and destroy his love the way he destroyed mine?
然后我听到了他们
There they were.
伊莎贝拉
Isabella!
我之前没提到过她 因为我没想到
I never mentioned her to you because it didn't occur to me.
她会和那些谋杀案有关
she was connected with the murders.
我来这儿后
Ever since I've been here,
遇见过许多不得安宁的鬼魂
I've come across restless spirits of all sorts.
他们大多忧伤 但无害
They're all kind of… sad, harmless.
而且最终 他们都会找到安宁
And eventually, the poor things go to their final rest.
等等 你的意思是 你能和鬼魂和平相处
Wait a second. S-so, you're just comfortable around ghosts?
我是个相信灵魂的人
As a spiritual person,
当然接受异度空间的存在
I've accepted many planes of existence.
我也说了 他们一般都不伤人的
And as I said, they've all been harmless.
伊莎贝拉是我的朋友
Isabella was my friend.
我们有许多共同点
We had a lot in common,
包括…
including…
痛苦的爱情经历
painful love lives.
我想保护她
I wanted to protect her.
你说她是三周前随着家族遗物
You said she showed up about three weeks ago.
一起来到这里的
when stuff from her home arrived?
是的 是跟蒂沃利修道院的一批物品一起来的
Yes, part of a shipment from a monastery in Tivoli.
她的家族和欧洲很多大家族一样
Her family's treasures found their way to the church,
物品都被捐入了教堂
as with many of the great houses of Europe.
你没注意到是她来了以后
You get that she got here.
谋杀才开始发生的吗
just before the murders started happening?
我才意识到
I finally realized that.
后来我听到了你们的话
And then I heard the two of you,
我开始起疑了
and it made me wonder.
所以我读了她的日记
That's when I read her journal.
她死后这本日记到了她父亲手里
It was given to her father right after her death.
怨鬼 和我们想的一样
Vengeful sprit, just like we thought.
可一个来自16世纪佛罗伦萨的鬼吗
Yeah, but 16th-century Florence.
她可能葬在佛罗伦萨了
She's probably buried in florence.
我猜也是
I assume.
她受审之后日记就结束了
The … the journal ended right after her trial.
皮耶罗的死太过可怕
Piero's death was so horrific,
她被判使用了巫术
she was convicted of witchcraft.
他们判她被绑在木桩上烧死
They sentenced her to burn at the stake.
好吧 假如她是烧死的
Okay, well, if she burned,
那她的骨头也应该烧没了
then so would her bones.
没错 但是 迪恩 这里有东西
Yeah, but, Dean, something here.
把她束缚在了这个地方
is the tether that ties her to this place.
八成是那本日记
It's probably the journal,
她在上面记录了自己的生活
where she wrote about her life.
我们看看能不能找到伊莎贝拉
Why don't see if we can find Isabella,
拖住她
try to slow her down.
萨姆 把这些东西全烧了
Sam, burn all this stuff.
她的…日记
Her…journal?
有这个必要吗
Is that necessary?
相信我 有必要
Believe me, it's necessary.
我可不确定 迪恩
Well, I don't know, Dean.
也许日记里还有什么信息
I mean, there might be more in here.
萨姆 烧了它
Sam, burn it.
走吧
Let's go.
我告诉你 我不知道别的了
I'm telling you I don't know any more.
你在撒谎 就像你这些年一直在散播我的谣言
You're lying, just as you lied about me all these years.
你怕我会找到所有失窃的魔药和咒语
You're afraid I'll recover all the stolen potions and spells.
然后变得比你更强大
and become more powerful than you.
可怜的罗威娜
Oh, poor, poor Rowena.
一次又一次地遭人密谋陷害
Always the victim of one conspiracy or another.
你如此渴望自己能变得强大
You're so consumed with your rise to power,
甚至看不清真相
you can't see the truth!
我看清了事实 而事实是如此可悲
I see the truth, and it's pathetic.
你任由这些记录者
You let these men of letters.
掠夺了世上最大的魔法秘密宝库
pillage the greatest trove of magical secrets in the world.
却无动于衷
and did nothing.
我们被削弱了
We were weakened.
被劫走的东西如今散播到世界各地的地堡中
The plunder was dispersed to bunkers all around the world.
那些地堡都受到严加保护
Those bunkers are powerfully warded.
我们没办法阻止他们
There was nothing we could do to stop them.
我要如何找到记录者
How do I find the men of letters?
我都不知道他们是不是还存在
I don't even know if they exist anymore.
我听说美国的分部
I've heard that the American chapter.
在50年代就灭绝了
was extinguished in the 1950s,
但显然 两名成员存活了下来
but apparently, two of its members survive …
那两个猎人 萨姆和迪恩·温彻斯特
The hunters, Sam and Dean Winchester.
温家兄弟吗
The Winchesters?
又是温家兄弟
Again with the Winchesters.
没完没了的温家兄弟
Perpetually, the Winchesters.
奥莉薇特 亲爱的
Olivette, dear…
虽然我们聊得很愉快
pleasant though this little chat has been,
但我觉得这次谈话…该结束了
I feel it's come… …to a close.
你的意思就是
What you're telling me.
巫师团不再强大了 因此
is that the coven is no longer all powerful and, therefore,
你也没用了
that you are no longer useful.
你最好小心点 罗威娜
You'd better be careful, Rowena.
有条界限你是不能跨越的
There's a line that cannot be crossed.
女巫相残在巫师界是滔天大罪
Witch-on-witch murder is anathema to the community.
巫师界
The community?
谁在乎他们啊
Who needs them?
一想到多年来我白白活在恐惧之中
To think of all the years I've lived in fear for nothing.
你毁了我的人生 奥莉薇特
You ruined my life, Olivette,
你要用你的命来偿还
and you shall pay with yours.
罗威娜 求你了 你不会想这么做的
Rowena, please, you don't want to do this.
求你了 罗威娜 别这样做
Please, Rowena, don't do this.
罗威娜 求你了
Rowena, please.
求你停下
Please stop.
[咒语]
停
Halt!
是我没想清楚
I haven't thought this through.
我为何要杀了你
Why should I kill you,
让你这么轻松地死去
give you an easy way out.
我明明有更好的选择
when there are far better options?
- [咒语] - 不要啊
- Fatum tuum est itersine… - No!
- [咒语] - 不要 罗威娜 求你了
- Termino ad nulum! - No! No! Rowena! Please!
不要啊
No!!
我真是个天才
Oh, I'm a genius.
假如她是与教堂束缚在一起
I don't see how she could murder these people.
她怎么能杀害这些人呢
if she was tethered to the church.
她可以在教堂里附上一个人的身
She could possess a person inside the church,
借那具身体离开
ride out,
杀人之后再被拉回来 所以…
and get yanked back after the kill, so…
鬼魂用枪杀得死吗
And can ghosts be shot?
这是岩盐子弹
This is rock salt.
如果我们发现她 这能拖住她
If we spot her, it'll slow her down.
日复一日 我对皮耶罗的爱越来越深
And as the days passed, my love for Piero deepened,
他也越来越相信 我是他的缪斯
as did his belief in my powers as his muse.
他说他想从我这里得到一样东西
He said he wanted something from me,
一样他都不敢问我要的东西
something he could barely give voice to.
他认为我对他作品的影响很深远
He thought the effect I had on his work was profound.
他以前从没画过这么好的
He had never painted so well before.
他问可否要我一点血
He asked if he might have a bit of my blood.
混在颜料中
to mix into the pigment.
皮耶罗很害怕他会伤到我
Piero was so afraid he would hurt me.
我告诉他 恰好相反 我很乐意这么做
I told him, on the contrary, it was my great joy to do this.
但这并不够
But it wasn't enough.
我让皮耶罗将肉 血和骨头研磨
I told Piero to grind the flesh, blood, and bone.
混入颜料
into the pigment.
我已经完全与画融为一体
I had completely become one with the painting.
- 也与皮耶罗融为一体 - 「融为一体」
- and with Piero. - "And with Piero"
她杀了德兰尼神父 她就在这附近
She got to father Delaney. She's around here somewhere.
我们得带你走 走吧
We got to get you out of here. Come on!
神父必须死
The priest had to die.
他一直宽恕你们这些臭男人
He made it his business to forgive you pigs…
宽恕你们不可饶恕的罪过
forgive you, when what you do is unforgivable.
萨姆 烧掉日记
Sam, burn the journal!
修女 别让他们这么做
Sister! Don't let them!
你是我的朋友
You are my friend.
你挺能跑啊
You're… ooh, you're trucking.
那是她吗
Is that her?
要我说 这才叫伸张正义
Poetic justice, if you ask me.
几百年来 那些老女人逼我卑躬屈膝
For hundreds of years, those hags made me grovel,
我企图讨好她们却只是徒劳
every attempt to please them futile.
也该让别的人跑圈圈了
high time someone else ran in circles, eh?
真有趣
Nice touch.
我也能想出这种点子
Something I might have thought of myself.
你看
You see?
我们也没那么不一样
We're not so very different.
你究竟想要什么
What is it that you want?
费格斯 既然你非要问
Well, Fergus, since you asked,
你的朋友 温家兄弟
these friends of yours… the Winchesters…
我听说他们是…怎么说的来着
I hear they are, oh, what do you call it, um,
记录者
men of letters?
可能吧
Possibly.
这样啊 这个…
I see. Well, about that…
听着 这事我们说过了
Listen, we've been through this.
我跟温家兄弟的关系是我的私事
My relationship with the Winchesters is my business.
我会对付他们 我不会杀了他们
I'll handle them. I'm not killing them.
好吧 亲爱的
All right, deary.
行啊
Of course.
听你的
Whatever you say.
什么人把血肉融入到颜料里啊
Who mixes their blood and bones into paint?
没有哪个女人为我做过这种事
No woman's ever done that for me.
你是在感谢我没听你的吗
Is this you thanking me for not doing what you told me to do?
如果你烧了日记
You know, if you would have burned the journal,
我们就无从得知怎么消灭她了
then we wouldn't know how to kill it, would we?
是啊 不客气
Yeah, you're welcome.
知道吗
You know…
你去忏悔了好长时间呢
you were in that confessional a long time.
伙计 我只是想说
Look, man, I'm just saying,
我是你弟弟 迪恩
I'm your brother, Dean.
如果你想跟谁说点什么话
If you ever need to talk about anything with anybody,
你身边就有个能倾诉的对象
you got somebody right here next to you.
好吧
Okay.
我听到了马赛厄斯修女说的话
I heard what sister Mathias was saying about, you know,
通过承担使命隐藏痛苦
hiding pain by taking on a mission,
我知道这也差不多就是你在做的
and I-I know that's what you're doing a little bit.
这没关系
And it's okay.
我能理解 我也这么做过
I mean, it's fine. I get it. I've done it before, too.
但是
But…
我绝不相信
I don't buy for one second.
血印就是绝症了
that the mark is a terminal diagnosis,
所以你别就这么接受了
so don't go making peace with that idea.
肯定是有办法的
There has to be a way.
肯定会有办法的 我们会找到办法的
There will be a way, and we will find it.
我们总是这样
That's what we do.
你要相信
So, believe that.
好吧 萨姆
Okay, Sammy.
要不要
You want to…
说得真心一点
Uh, try that again like you mean it?
好
Okay.